<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Development on // fBrx </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://fbrx.github.io/categories/development/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 17:35:43 CET</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://fbrx.github.io/post/hugo-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 17:35:43 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://fbrx.github.io/post/hugo-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a static CMS system. In this case static means, that all the content is rendered to static html markup. So there is no need for anything else than a HTTP server to run your site. This makes the whole thing a lot less complicated as well as a lot more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content for a site which is generated by Hugo is generally edited in &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; files. This gives you the possibility to edit everything disconnected as well as choose the tools you like for your writing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; (which you probably should anyway) just &lt;code&gt;brew install hugo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Create your first site&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo provides so called builders. Builders can be used to generate specific items like pages, blog posts and whole sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site builder is invoked as follows: &lt;code&gt;hugo new site /path/to/your/site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes&amp;hellip;thats it. Hugo just created a minimal site structure with all files and folders needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Install themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo provides a set of themes which are all hosted on github. To use a theme, it has to be copied to the local site structure under the themes folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install all available themes go to your working directory and clone the corresponding git repository: &lt;code&gt;git clone --recursive https://github.com/spf13/hugoThemes themes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Run your site locally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just run &lt;code&gt;hugo server -D -w -t hyde&lt;/code&gt; from your working directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;-D&lt;/code&gt;switch tells Hugo to generate and display pages, which are marked as drafts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; Hugo will be monitoring the working directory for any changes and publish them immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To select the theme which should be used to generate the site the &lt;code&gt;-t &amp;lt;theme name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; option is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>